Finding Aid for the Pierce and Company, San Francisco Records, 1853-1902 LSC.2043
UCLA Library Special Collections
Pierce and Company, San Francisco Records
1853-1902
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2043
1.5 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
General note
Ex libris Robert Ernest Cowan
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942335883606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, newspaper clippings, bills, accounts, receipts, and other business papers of the baking firm of Pierce and Company, San Francisco. Includes material relating to the wheat trade and shipping. Also includes personal letters and papers for William, Henry, Ira, and Lewis Pierce.
Bakers and bakeries -- California -- San Francisco -- Archives.; Pierce and Company, San Francisco -- Archives
- Pierce, Henry and William
  - Letters to the Pierces from various persons., 1854-1865.; 86 letters, 89 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters to the Pierces from various persons., 1866.; 96 letters, 96 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Letters to the Pierces from various persons., 1867-1898.; 48 letters, 48 pieces. Some letters are undated. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drafts and copies of letters to various persons from the Pierces., 1868-1870.; 5 letters, 5 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pierce
  - Letters to various persons from various persons., 1858-1881.; 18 letters, 21 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Pierce Family
  - Letters to Henry, William, Lewis and Ira Pierce from various persons. and, 1853-1870 n.d.; 38 letters, 39 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Legal papers., 1853-l903.; 23 documents. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Pierce & Company, San Francisco
  - Business papers., 1857-1870.; 53 documents. 54 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous papers: newspaper clippings, description of Pierces' warehouse in Suisin City, California, advertising cards, etc., 1862, 1865 and n.d.; 25 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Pierce, Henry
  - Letters from various persons., 1865-1873.; 76 letters. 94 pieces. Some letters are undated. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters from various persons., 1859-1864.; 76 letters. 76 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Pierce, Ira
  - Letters from Henry and William Pierce., Jul-Dec 1866.; 17 letters. 18 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Pierce, Lewis
  - Letters from various parsons., 1861-1371.; 67 letters. 67 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Pierce, William
  - Letters from various persons., 1859-1864.; 178 letters. 183 pieces. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters from various persons., 1865-1871.; 92 letters. 111 pieces. Some letters are undated. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bills, Accounts, Receipts
  - 1850., 6 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1852., 193 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1853., 216 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1854., 168 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1855., 169 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1856., 115 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1857., 153 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1858., 143 pieces. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1859., 92 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1860., 95 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1861., 144 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1862., 104 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1863., 103 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1864., 107 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1865., 62 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1866., 20 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1867., 14 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1868-1870., 49 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1872-1902., 59 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - n.d., 49 pieces. (Box 3, Folder 12)